<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-07-26T16:59:25-04:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">gerard’s site</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Back to school</title><link href="/2025/07/26/Back-to-school.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to school" /><published>2025-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2025/07/26/Back-to-school</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/07/26/Back-to-school.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’ll be going back to school this September. I feel really… “overwhelmed.” I hate using that word. It sounds like I’m that kind of person that uses therapy-speak to paint myself as a victim, or to justify being incapable of doing anything. I dunno how else to explain it. Like most of my posts, this is honestly just going to be me rambling. No structure or anything. Honestly, even as I type this out, I can feel the points I wanted to go over draining out of my brain.</p>

<p>But anyways — yeah, I’m going back to school this September. Good ol’ UTSC. You know, I used to kind of resent going there. And I still kind of do, to an extent. It always sort of felt like the place where all the people who got rejected from St. George go. But that might just be me. Most people going to university were far more prepared than I ever was. And that’s on me. I dove right in, expecting everything to just work out. Spoiler alert: it didn’t. And that’s how you end up with a self-loathing, anti-social, genuinely resentful slob who hates doing anything that requires even a fraction of brainpower.</p>

<p>I’m scared, at the end of the day. I really am. This past year, I’ve been just living with my parents and relaxing. I haven’t been able to find work unfortunately, so I’ve basically been a NEET for a year. I’m not trying to make that sound nice. It sucks. Oh, I forgot to mention why I took a break from school in the first place. Basically, my grades were <em>really</em> bad, so I was put under probation, and since I wasn’t able to get them up, I was booted. Twice, actually. The first time was four months. I flunked all of my classes that year. Second year of university. Then, after that, I managed to finally pass my courses in my third year. That was a really big achievement for me, honestly. It felt like I was finally getting everything back together. But I passed through the skin of my teeth, so I was then suspended for a year.</p>

<p>I’ve had a lot of time to reflect on everything. That’s what I’ve been doing for the past four years, honestly. I’ve talked to some people about my mental health. A counselor, a psychologist, my friends, whatever. I dunno. I never really liked talking about it much. What I dislike about mental health professionals is that they often try to find the root of your problems, but it doesn’t seem effective to me because I knew exactly what was causing them. It was because I was behind in school. That I couldn’t pass anything. I felt like an idiot. Especially since I was surrounded by, genuinely, extremely bright people. Doesn’t help that I look at everyone else in my classes and I see that they’re all younger than me.</p>

<p>Oh man, I’ve been circling about what I wanted to vent about in the first place. Ugh, looking for housing is so stressful. Luckily, I’ve been trying to get on that earlier than I usually do, so stuff seems to be cheaper than how it usually is for. I’m grateful for that. But housing aside, I still haven’t picked out my courses. ACORN says that I haven’t been invited to the fall semester, so I emailed the registrar about that. Ahh, man. Deadlines always stress me out. It feels really demeaning not being able to handle these things as well as everybody else seems to be able to. God, and then there’s still the money I need to worry about. I have some funds saved up, but I’m going to need to find a job in Toronto so I can pay for rent and tuition comfortably. I really hate relying on OSAP. Being in debt stresses me the fuck out.</p>

<p>I want to somehow scream in text form. I’ll try it right now: AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAADAWBDIHUABWDUHYABWDUYAWVG DUYAWGUID UJWAGDJUHYAWGJIUDHBIWUAHDWIAIDOEWORH98QU89HDAIDAQWADWQDPHNIQWQWDPKNIWQDPHIQWDH08ADAWDAWEHIAHDOIADLDONAWDNOHALOIWUA0P;D JAWFP;NA;IOAFUVC  MUFCK QIUWFDUIAWHWUIOJAFUCKAWDHAWHDWUIAHD OIAJUWOD JOWIAJDOIAJWDJOAWJDOIWNADOWAU9FDHAWFNOIAWNJFOIAWNFOAWINFIOWYAOR WANDRKJABNDOIWNADPIONKLW JMKAFDAIW</p>

<p>I threw in some keysmashes. For extra flavor, and I also just felt the need to smash my keyboard. Stressful things are going on right now. For me, at least. I’m sure that for the average person, this is nothing. I just gotta man up and start being an adult. Sigh.</p>

<p>Oh, yeah, forgot to mention. I’ve been working on a Neocities website and I’ll probably migrate to blogposting over there. The url is <a href="https://procinogen.neocities.org">procinogen.neocities.org</a>. As of the time of writing this, it just links back to this website.</p>

<p>It makes more sense to me if this was a more professional website. I have an article that I’ve been working on about the mechanics of braking in skateboarding. Hopefully that ends up seeing the light of day.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[it's been a year]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The average person is a nobody</title><link href="/2025/07/06/The-average-person-is-a-nobody.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The average person is a nobody" /><published>2025-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2025/07/06/The-average-person-is-a-nobody</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2025/07/06/The-average-person-is-a-nobody.html"><![CDATA[<p>God - do you know how long it took to get this working again? I update my site maybe, like, once every two years. I want to try changing that, but that’s kind of wishful thinking for now. I spent at least an hour trying to sift through gems and dependencies only to finally check Jekyll’s github and see that I needed to update the version of Jekyll listed in the gemfile. I’m not very good at this. That’s the end of this little rant. Back to our regularly scheduled programming.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<hr />

<p><br /></p>

<p>I have a lot of thoughts that I wish I would put on here. But that requires getting up and writing them down. But it can’t really be that hard, right? I don’t know why I never seem to have the willpower to do that. Part of me thinks that it’s because I know that dealing with all the updating would be a nightmare - and it is - but I guess that it would be better to deal with it as it comes instead of letting it pile up and kill me all at once. Anyways.</p>

<p>I’ve been thinking about how bleak it is that the average person is ultimately just a nobody. The average person is… well, average. Shocker. Some could argue that’s it’s systemic in nature, that the powers that be designed society in such a way that it becomes hard to stand out or whatever. And that’s definitely true about some stuff: Oh, the horrors of capital, the industrial military complex, nationalism, et cetera, et cetera. But that isn’t what I’m talking about. By <em>definition</em>, the <em>average</em> person can’t stand out, because if they did, then they wouldn’t be average. I guess that “nobody” is too harsh of a word. But, you know, you get what I mean. Not everybody can be exceptional.</p>

<p>Can you believe what got me spiraling into this thought? A Minecraft video. A fucking Minecraft video. It was a three minute video of the members showing off their technical server. They had world record farms and stuff. It’s not like, a Nobel Peace Prize, and a lot of people would say that those guys are just wasting their time. But now I know that those people <em>exist.</em> Thousands of people know that they exist. That’s so much more than what the average person can say. That’s so much more than what I can say.</p>

<p>I’m being too cynical. I know that. The average person isn’t really a “nobody.” I loathe the rising philosophy that most people are NPCs. Everybody has their own rich, colourful, internal world, and they mean so much to everybody else that they know. They’re thinking, living, breathing, people. And whether or not I know them, or acknowledge them, they exist. I think calling the average person a “nobody” is definitely a projection of how hollow my life feels most of the time.</p>

<p>I want to write more, but there isn’t much else for me to say here. Well, there probably is, but I guess I haven’t thought that far.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[passing thoughts from a self-loathing personality]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">At a Certain Point, Everything is a Choice</title><link href="/2024/04/25/At-a-certain-point-everything-is-a-choice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="At a Certain Point, Everything is a Choice" /><published>2024-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-04-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2024/04/25/At-a-certain-point-everything-is-a-choice</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2024/04/25/At-a-certain-point-everything-is-a-choice.html"><![CDATA[<p>Life for me has been hard for the past four years. Hard? Hard is one way of putting it. Sure. I mean, I understand that life for me isn’t really “hard”. I live in a pretty good country, I have good friends and a loving family, I go to a good school, I have a roof over my head and a full belly (when I remember to eat, at least), but despite all that, I have the gall to say that life has been hard - only to undermine how I feel but highlighting how, in fact, my life is not as hard as I just said it was. If you couldn’t already tell, this won’t be a well-structured essay this time around. And I’ll probably just sort of be meandering from topic to topic based on whenever I remember it. But hey, this is <em>my</em> blog, so I can blogpost whenever I feel like it.</p>

<p>On a completely unrelated note, do you know how hard it is using jekyll on arch? (I use <del>Arch</del> Manjaro btw.) It sucks! Or maybe I do. Running <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">bundle exec jekyll serve</code> just wasn’t working for like, ten minutes. I did manage to find a workaround my adding <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">gem "json"</code> in the gemfile, though. Apparently jekyll isn’t playing nice with my operating system’s json packages, or something like that. Maybe it’s a sign that I need to update my packages (it’s been… four months. I’ve been too busy to update it. I mean, I could just run it, but then some stuff might break, and I don’t want to deal with that with a bunch of assignments due.) You know, I’ve never really played around with the markdown styling before. Well, I have, when I made the theme for this site, which was fun. But I’ve never used the codeblocks.</p>

<p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">It's cool stuff.</code></p>

<p>Tangents aside, I’ve been frustrated with how things have been going. Really frustrated. To put it really bluntly, it often feels like I need to put in exponentially more effort than everyone else just to breathe the same air as them. I feel like I try so hard, only for my effort to go to waste. I’ve been held back so long now. I have an exam tomorrow, too. Yeah. And I should be studying for that instead. But I feel like I study any more, my brain is going to fucking melt. But, y’know, I guess that’s a choice I need to make. Maybe. I don’t know. It’s just really discouraging, I guess. Yeah. Discouraging. I hate this. I hate everything. Not really.</p>

<p>You know, I finally got around to seeing the cherry blossoms that are on campus. I’ve always been so busy with trying not to fucking kill myself that I never ended up seeing them bloom in the spring. Until now, obviously. Oh boy, this is <em>not</em> going on my site now. I guess I’ll just throw this onto my Pleroma. Everything is so discouraging. On the bright side, I passed two courses. That isn’t a lot for most people, but for me it is. See what I mean? Even <em>passing</em> is such an achievement for me. <em>Fucking passing.</em> The effort I have to put in compared to everyone else is ridiculous. And I’m not trying to paint the picture that my life is unfair - this is entirely my own fault. Everything is my fault. I can keep trying to put in all the effort I want, but nothing good ever happens. I don’t know what I’m even talking about anymore. My fingers are just kind of moving by themselves now. Just typing the strings of words that come to mind, without really thinking about what those words are, really. I wonder if meta-analysis of my own blogpost as I’m writing it takes away from its quality. It probably does. There’s a weird sort of irony that comes from thinking about what to think, which you’ll be writing down. I’m not trying to be random. I’m just writing whatever comes to mind because I don’t know what else to write. I started writing this post because I wanted to vent. I wanted to just vent about how much I fucking hate everything, despite how good everything is for me. But things turned out even less structured than I had initially planned for it to. I don’t know. My eyes are dry. Maybe I’ll stop for now. I don’t know.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="academia" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Rambling]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Collection of Poems I Wrote</title><link href="/2023/04/13/A-Collection-of-Poems.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Collection of Poems I Wrote" /><published>2023-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2023/04/13/A-Collection-of-Poems</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2023/04/13/A-Collection-of-Poems.html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="untitled-021323">Untitled (02/13/23)</h3>

<p>one day<br />
i will die<br />
and my body will rot;<br />
maggots will feast on my flesh -<br />
worms fill where my eyes<br />
once were and i will be thought<br />
of for the very last time</p>

<h3 id="untitled-041323">Untitled (04/13/23)</h3>

<p>I know summer - sunlight, warmth, rest, - is right before me;<br />
I can taste the cold, crisp, beers;<br />
I can hear my friends’ carefree conversations;<br />
I can feel -</p>

<p>Entropy:<br />
Chaos increases - heat-energy spreads.<br />
Phase shift:<br />
Matter transitions - water boils.<br />
Exothermic:<br />
Energy released - matter cools.<br />
the psyche:<br />
seasons change. hearts freeze.<br />
time:<br />
passes.</p>

<h3 id="untitled-041323-1">Untitled (04/13/23)</h3>

<p>Integrate:<br />
determine its volume -<br />
Derive:<br />
how quickly it changes -<br />
Limit:<br />
how close did it get? -<br />
Substitute:<br />
pretend its something else -<br />
Evaluate:<br />
“Unnecessary.”<br />
Closure:<br />
alone.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="poetry" /><category term="writing" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Surprise surprise, I enjoy creative writing.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Death of Passion</title><link href="/2022/04/29/the-death-of-passion.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Death of Passion" /><published>2022-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2022/04/29/the-death-of-passion</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/04/29/the-death-of-passion.html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="passion">passion</h4>
<p>/ˈpaSHən/</p>

<p> 5 a : ardent affection; love</p>

<p> 2 <em>obsolete</em>: suffering</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h4 id="treading-water">Treading Water</h4>
<p> Over the past handful of years, I have had a complicated relationship with mathematics and science. My love for the subject has waned back and forth, just as a tide closes in on the shore only to disappear in what seems like moments after; the peaks and dips connecting in a sinusoidal dance, growing ever more intense with the completion of each wavelength; the crests and troughs racing along the invisible asymptotic line illustrating my affection and anger towards the concept as a whole. Of course, this is normal. Perhaps this case is more extreme than others, but the general cyclic nature of interest is intrinsic to any person and their passions.</p>

<p> As a child, I was mesmerized by the world of science and mathematics. Nothing would hold my attention more than seeing the universe’s nature being laid out in front of me. My desire to know seemed entirely insatiable: there was a constant torrent of “why?”s and “how?”s spewing out of my mouth, filling my search history and the ears of those around me. For most of my education, this drive was enough to push me to soaring heights. Honour roll after honour roll, I dove headfirst into the world of academics and thrived. I loved it all. I truly did. As my brain feasted on the cerebral sweets my passion for science and mathematics grew exponentially.</p>

<p> I loved the sciences. It was my passion. It was an integral part of my identity; so much of who was “me” was derived from the subject. But at some point, I stumbled. In the vast sea of academics, I was drowning. I sputtered, gasped, and begged for air: the cold, uncaring expanse embraced me with the warmth and softness of a metal coffin. The ocean that had once been my passion was now suffocating.</p>

<p> I think that “interest” is comprised of multiple levels, all of which are dependent on the intellectual stimulation and the contextual environment of the subject at hand. While I swam deeper and deeper into my intellectual and academic pursuits, the pressure slowly built up. I could feel an ever-increasing force applied across my whole being. Before I could react, I was in too deep - expectations, deadlines, and desires had consumed the forefront of my mind. First, passion turned to boredom; boredom turned to disinterest; from disinterest came disgust. While I struggled to breathe in the depths of scholarship, I grew bitter. As I floated back to the surface to swallow my first breath in years, I would never forget the embarrassment and betrayal I had felt. The sensation of my lungs filling to the brim: the suffocating nature of the ocean. Was I too ambitious? Or was I not as talented as I had believed?</p>

<p> Too much of anything is a bad thing. This statement holds true for many things in life: confectionaries, vitamins, minerals, and namely, <em>passion</em>. If I were to have all the chocolate in the world, I would eventually become bored of it. I was surrounded by the academic ocean from all sides. Unlike chocolate, I was dependent on my passion. Unlike chocolate, if I was not able to use my passion to keep up with the flow of the sea around me, I would die. From then on, each passing second fueled my disinterest in the sciences and hatred for academia. The nature of my environment demanded that I would have expressions of my passion extracted, then examined, and scrutinized, selecting every single misstep and dragging me further into the murky depths. I was tired. Exhausted. I did not want any more of this. I wanted to rest.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h4 id="burnout">Burnout</h4>
<p> What passion leaves behind is mostly bittersweet memories of when love was still present. While any passion can become burnt out, I feel as though passion in science and mathematics can be differentiated. Unlike, for example, the visual arts, mathematics and science is taken much more “seriously.” A child with a passion for visual art can take classes for it, but it is not something that is required. Again, this is not to say that the artistically inclined do not have their own struggles, pressures, and burnouts, but I do think that it is different than the mathematically/scientifically inclined experience. Mathematics is something that a child will be rigorously tested for throughout their development. This can change how they will think of their passion - their talent and performance are things that should, and will, be marked. While this is not the case for every academically inclined child, I feel as though this situation happens enough for it to be further examined.</p>

<p> With the constant need to apply their passion at school, a dissonance forms between “hobby” and “passion.” Why is it that you rarely see a child doing calculations outside of school, whereas it is extremely common to see children drawing or playing sports? Besides the obvious answer that “it’s boring,” I believe that this is caused by how mathematical and scientific talent is treated. Their passion becomes associated with work - “why would I study math now if I just spent all day at school practicing it?”</p>

<p> Not every child is able to keep up with the demands and needs of school and will fall behind. The idea that their talent is something that will be marked will often stay with them and linger in the back of their consciousness. The combination of lackluster performance and the (often merely perceived) expectations of the world around them can eat away at their passion and self-esteem. This can be thought of as unintentional conditioning: their passion is now associated with poor reception, leading to a large disinterest, and worse, a distaste for the subjects that they had loved. This dispassion may worsen when they enter high school and post-secondary education. Expectations tighten. And now, academic performance matters. As opposed to elementary education, there is a very real threat from lackluster marks. Underperformance, pressure of university acceptances, university tuition fees, and degree completion can be soul-crushing.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h4 id="the-academic-self">The Academic Self</h4>
<p> Identity is not a fundamental aspect of a person. Rather, it is the culmination of all the fundamental aspects of a person to which they apply to themself. Athleticism, creativity, and intellectualism are all aspects that a person may use to form their identity. One’s identity, however, may not need to be based wholly on reality - this results in an “ill-fit” identity. Perhaps one believes that they are more athletic than their body will actually allow for. Due to the fluid nature of a person’s aspects, the vast majority of people will have identities that are not 100% aligned with their “true” self. As life continues, they will be affected by those around them and learn. Their identity will slowly align progressively better with their “true self,” resulting in an identity that they can comfortably apply to themself. However, environmental factors may not always result in a “well-fit” identity.</p>

<p> What if the environment were to teach a person that a certain trait was a fundamental aspect of their being when it is not? One’s passions are likely to be used as aspects to culminate their identity. A passion for cooking lends itself easily to the identity of a chef, amateur or professional. How is this process affected when the sense of their passion is warped?</p>

<p> In the case of academics, the sense of passion may be warped through the factors I have outlined prior; I will not reiterate them as it would be redundant. To put it simply, the passion for the sciences is warped into what seems like a passion for high academic performance. When this mismatched passion is used to form an identity, it creates a dissonance in the person’s mind. As the person develops and grows they will continue to think that school, and more specifically, high grades, are a part of their identity. If their performance begins to dip, it affects their identity alongside it. The visible gap between who they thought they were and who they are in that instance may lead to severe damage - it annihilates their sense of self.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h4 id="closing-thoughts">Closing Thoughts</h4>
<p> Perhaps everything I have written is completely incorrect. I would not know - everything I have experienced has been through my own eyes and I have never explored these thoughts with others. More will be written in the future as I collect more thoughts and explore the idea further. Regardless, I feel as though these writings accurately detail my ideas and philosophies regarding the nature of academia and its influence on passion. Burning out and losing one’s sense of self are dangerous paths for one to go down - I hope that what I have written may give further insight into the topic and maybe even prevent others from feeling what I have felt. Thank you for reading.</p>

<hr />

<p>Merriam-Webster. (n.d.). Passion. <em>In Merriam-Webster.com dictionary.</em> Retrieved April 29, 2022, from https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/passion</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="personal" /><category term="academia" /><category term="science" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of thoughts regarding academia and its effect on scientific and mathematical interest.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I hate Instagram’s APIs</title><link href="/2022/04/15/ig-api-sucks.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I hate Instagram’s APIs" /><published>2022-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2022-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2022/04/15/ig-api-sucks</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2022/04/15/ig-api-sucks.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m trying to add a feature to this site that shows a feed of my Instagram account’s post. However, the gods over at facebook have so valiantly decided that I would need to go through this strenuous process to authenticate my usage of their API. All I want to do is to show my account’s feed in the form of embeds.</p>

<p>I am looking into other social media platforms that allow me to do this. I think Twitter might have this functionality but I’ll have to look into it. Might be a reason to start using it more. If anyone reading this has any ideas, don’t hesitate to <a href="/socials">let me know</a>.</p>

<p>Honestly this post is kind of just filler.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="instagram" /><category term="api" /><category term="rant" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm trying to add a feature to this site that shows a feed of my instagram account's post.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An Analysis of the Brain-in-a-Vat Argument</title><link href="/2021/12/17/biv-analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Analysis of the Brain-in-a-Vat Argument" /><published>2021-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/12/17/biv-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/12/17/biv-analysis.html"><![CDATA[<p> Suppose that a character, Bivvie, is a brain in a vat (BIV) – Bivvie’s reality is “false” as it is constructed by some external actor by feeding Bivvie’s brain different signals that are used to construct their reality. Despite actually being a BIV, Putnam argues that Bivvie is completely unable to actually say that they are a BIV. This conclusion draws from two key ideas: resemblance and intention/depiction.</p>

<p> To explain both of these ideas, we will use one of Putnam’s examples: suppose that an ant is walking along the ground, unknowingly leaving a line behind in the dirt. Miracuously, the image that the ant has left behind bears a striking resemblance to the former Prime Minster of the UK, Winston Churchill. If one were then asked, did the ant depict Winston Churchil? Intuitively, most people would say no. This is due to the simple fact that despite the ant’s “drawing” resembling Churchill, it did not intend to draw Churchill. Churchill is far beyond the ant’s limited knowledge – the ant is unaware of who Churchill is, or even the fact that it was “drawing” anything to begin with. This examples serves to illustrate how resemblance is not a sufficient condition for depiction. The ant’s drawing resembles that of a person, but that does not imply that it is a depiction of a person.</p>

<p> We can further build apon this logic using a more abstract conjecture. Suppose that you are having a conversation with an atrificial intelligence, programmed to perfectly replicate human discourse. If one were to ask it, “How is the weather today?” it may reply, “It is very windy today.” If we are to strip away the AI’s interface what would be left is a program – an algorithm designed to react in a specific way given a certain stimulus. The fact that the AI spoke about the weather like a human does not mean that it “knows” about the weather. Simply put, the AI has no idea of what weather is. The AI has never experienced the weather as we have – it is simply reading data. To further exemplify this, if I were to ask the AI, “Do you like the weather today?” and it were to respond, “Yes, I like how windy it is today,” the AI does not “like” the “weather”. To the AI, what it interprets as the “weather” is far removed from our experience of the weather. Similar to the situation with the ant, the AI’s words bear resemblance to an understanding of the weather, but they do not actually depict a person who has experienced the weather.</p>

<p> With this context in mind, it is now possible give a proper analysis of the BIV situation. If Bivvie were to say, “I am a brain in a vat,” the statement is inherently false. This again draws from the key ideas of resemblance and depiction. Suppose that Bivvie’s reality is controlled by a mad scientist who is feeding signals to Bivvie’s brain, and that this mad scientist exists in a world similar to ours, with the certainty that he is not a BIV. If Bivvie (in their falsified reality) points at a tree, what are they truly saying? The tree that they are pointing at is a simulated tree (sTree). They are unable to point at it and say that it is a real tree (rTree) without the statement being false. So the statement “That is a tree,” implicitly turns into “That is an sTree.” This logic extends to when Bivvie questions the nature of their reality as well. If Bivvie says that “I am a BIV,” their statement refers to a simulated BIV-scenario (sBIV) and not a “real” BIV-scenario (rBIV). Similar to the tree, the statement “I am a BIV” implicitly turns into “I am an sBIV,” which is inherently false. Even if Bivvie were to say, “I am an rBIV, ” it would then be the same as saying, “I am in srBIV,” as Bivvie has only ever experienced what it is like in their falsified reality. As such, Bivvie has as no concept of what an “rBIV” would be. They can imagine the concept of one, the limited scope of their knowledge means that anything they can conceptualize will implicitly be a “simulated” version. Bivvie’s statement merely resembles that of a “real” “I am a BIV” statement, and does not actually depict one.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="works-cited">Works Cited</h4>

<p>Putnam, Hilary (1999). Brains in a Vat. In Sven Bernecker &amp; Fred I. Dretske (eds.), <em>Knowledge: Readings in Contemporary Epistemology.</em> Oxford University Press. pp. 1-21.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="simulation-theory" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an essay detailing my thoughts on simulation theory and the BIV argument.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Meaning of Morality: Stevenson’s Analysis on the Magnetism of Goodness</title><link href="/2021/11/16/the-meaning-of-morality.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Meaning of Morality: Stevenson’s Analysis on the Magnetism of Goodness" /><published>2021-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-11-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/2021/11/16/the-meaning-of-morality</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/11/16/the-meaning-of-morality.html"><![CDATA[<p> In Stevenson’s The Emotive Meaning of Ethical Terms, he discusses the nature of “goodness” and what it means for any particular idea or “thing” to be good (p. 16). Specifically, Stevenson describes “goodness” to be “magnetic” – my belief in X to be good compels me to act in X’s favour. To further understand this concept, it is important to contextualize it with previous theories regarding goodness. To begin, one must understand the core idea(s) from which ethical questions arise: “Is X good?” or “Is this better than that?”  Stevenson states that such questions are difficult to answer, and he elaborates, “we are asking, ‘Is there a needle in that haystack?’ without even knowing just what a needle is.’ To circumvent this issue, it is possible to distill the question into a clearer, less vague one (as not to completely change the initial question, of course). (p. 1). For example, the question “Is X good?” can be restated as “Does X do Y?” where Y is of relevance to the goodness of X. However, a paradoxical situation arises – the question seems to have become more vague! This stems from a further underlying issue: what is the definition of “good”?</p>

<p> There have been many different interpretations of  the term “good” throughout philosophy and history. Stevenson describes two of these interpretations; Hobbes’ interpretation, “good is what is desired by me”; and Humes’ interpretation, “good is what is approved by moth people.” These interpretations may be called interest theories – “good” simply describes the current state of the speaker or majority’s wants (p. 15). For example, suppose that I were to say, “Stealing from me is not good.” According to interest theories, what I am saying may be substituted as, “I do not want you to steal from me,” or, “Society states that you must not steal from me.”</p>

<p> 	Stevenson presents “goodness” as being more than descriptive; “goodness” is emotive. 
To prove this, we may do further probing of interest theories. Suppose that person A and person B are debating the goodness of X. Person A says, “X is good.” Person B says, “X is not good.” The back and forth between persons A and B can be simplified to a conflict of interest; “I like X,” versus “I don’t like X.”  According ot Hobbes’ interest theory, both of these people are correct in their statements – this does not make intuitive sense. This may be sensible in regards to small-scale issues, but as to larger, more directly opposing views, how can both person A and B be correct? To further exemplify the deeper unintuitiveness, we may look at Hume’s interpretation of goodness. Suppose that crowd A strongly votes in favor of some object, X. Despite the majority of people thinking in favor of  X, person B has no reason to believe that X is good. For example, imagine the majority of a country being strongly in favour of a genocide – despite the consesus being largely in favor of genocide, you may think, “No, I do no think that is good.” (p. 17). Stevenson’s analysis of “good” draws much of its evidence in language – how are words used, and what exactly is the intent and meaning behind what someone says? What exactly is meant by “magnetism”?</p>

<p> When I say, “Stealing is not good,” what is my intent behind the statement? Stevenson states that there are two different purposes in our use of language – recording and communicating beliefs (descriptively) , and to vent emotion and incite action (emotively/dynamically) (p. 21). Magnetism draws from the second purpose; when I say, “Stealing is not good,” I am attempting to persuade the listener to share this belief. Suppose that I suggest, “Stealing from the rich is good.” Person B interjects, and says, “I don’t like it.” Despite being a perfectly valid response, it feels unnatural. The unnaturalness draws from the assumption that my statement was being used descriptively – B assumed that my statement meant, “We/I like stealing from the rich.” (p. 24).  A more natural (and more apt) response would be something along the lins of, “Why?” or, “I disagree, here is why…” This form of response draws from the idea that what I had said was dynamic – I am trying to convince B of my statement’s superiority.</p>

<p> According to Stevenson, ethical terms are “instruments used in the complicated interplay and readjustment of human interests,” which can be seen through general observations (p. 20). It is well known that people have a tendency to separate into groups of similar interests, each group harboring their own moral perspectives. The people in these social strata are influenced by the greater social interpersonal interactions that they find themselves apart of. While the physical state a person may find themselves in will influence their beliefs and what they determine to be “good”, it would be disingenuine to assume that the words of others does not play a part in influencing a person’s ethical views. When those in power declare something to be “good”, their statement influences the beliefs of others If this ruler simply wanted to declare their opinion on something, what would be purpose of announcing it to the body they govern? The magnetism that “goodness” has plays an intrinsic part in the behaviour of people and their intentions. To further describe this phenomena, Stevenson writes, “When a person likes something, he is pleased when it prospers, and disappointed when it doesn’t. When a person morally approves of something, he experiences a rich feeling of security when it propsers, amd is indignant, or ‘shocked’ when it doesn’t.”</p>

<p>  One glaring criticism of Stevenson’s analysis is that the question, “Is X good?” does not have the mere intent of influencing or asking for advice; while the answer will still influence the asker’s interests, this is solely due to the asker’s belief in X’s goodness to be driven by “truth,” where “truth” is reasoned deductively through learned the information learned through the answer (p. 30). Stevenson counters with the point that we cannot truly define what truth is when asking this question; we do not have a clear answer that we are looking for (“What does good mean in this context?”). This reflects the earlier points made of the vagueness of “goodness,” which then evolves into the idea of magnetism.</p>

<p> It is important to note Stevenon’s utilitarian description of  “good.” Stevenson’s analysis is wholly detached from how ethical “should” be used and instead focuses on “why” they are used; Magnetism disregards the metaphysical idea of “goodness” being an innate feature, but instead that “goodness” is a method of spreading influence. To draw from one of his examples: A munition maker declares that war is a good thing. If the maker was merely describing his beliefs, he would not be insisting his opinion so strongly. Furthermore, if he was stating that the majority of people were in favour of war, not only would he be incorrect but he would be forced to prove it by the listeners. Instead, he is attempting to influence others in his beliefs, as proven by the numerous examples from earlier in this paper. Stevenson’s analysis does not attempt to claim that the maker’s use of  “good” in and of itself, but his analysis is simply describing how it was being used. (p. 19-20).</p>

<p> Another key idea that Stevenson’s analysis ultimately proves is that no person is in a better position to make the claim “X is good” than another. As Stevenson has been discussing, the statement “X is good” is a “vehicle of suggestion.” (p. 30). By the very nature of this statement, Stevenson’s analysis of “good” prevents certain ethical statements to be more “correct” than others. Throughout this paper I have used examples in which you may have obvious or intuitive moralistic opinions on. However, your ethical claims in response to these examples, whether for or against, are not any more “correct” than the ethical statements that I have used for examples (assuming that “goodness” is not being used descriptively). Even here, good’s magnetism may be seen – the need to object and correct these examples is further proof that when the statement “X is good” is uttered, it is not being used as a mere description. The discourse that happens between two opposing ideas on the goodness of X, while it may contain certain descriptive elements, is ultimately a battle of suggestion rather than a battle of the scientific method. Intuitively we know this; an ethical debate is not held to describe our beliefs, but is used to persuade others into the same belief.</p>

<hr />

<h4 id="works-cited">Works Cited</h4>
<p>Stevenson, Charles Leslie (1937). <em>The emotive meaning of ethical terms.</em> Oxford: Oxford University Press.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="philosophy" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[To understand the nature of “goodness,” one must understand the core idea(s) from which ethical questions arise: “Is X good?”]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Function and Mechanisms of Semiconductor Materials</title><link href="/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Function and Mechanisms of Semiconductor Materials" /><published>2021-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials.html"><![CDATA[<p> Society is filled to the brim with a plethora of electrical devices, such as computers, phones, and even simple calculators. Such technology is made possible through the application of semiconductor materials. A semiconductor is a material that has an electrical conductivity that lies between that of an electrical conductor (mainly metals, such as copper and aluminum) and an electrical insulator (such as rubber or wood), with the most common semiconductor materials being silicon and germanium. Semiconductor materials operate on two main principles: bandgap and doping. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>

<p> Everything in the universe is composed of atoms. Atoms have electron orbitals, also known as shells which can be thought of as the “path” that an electron takes when orbiting around the atoms’ nucleus. When atoms combine on the macroscopic level, the shells combine together to form bands. The filled, lower energy orbitals are known as the valence band. Electrons in the valence band are still bound too strongly to their atoms’ nucleus, and can not conduct an electric current. The empty, higher energy orbitals are known as the conduction bands. The electrons, when in the conduction bands, require little energy to move freely and can conduct an electric current. The distance between the valence band and the conduction band is known as the material’s bandgap, and is responsible for a material’s conductivity. Electrically resistant materials have a very high bandgap, while electrically conductive materials have a very low bandgap. Semiconductive materials have a bandgap that lies between that of a resistor and a conductor, so adding energy to the system (e.g. heating) allows the electrons to more easily move to the conduction band. It is the ability to control the material’s conductivity that gives semiconductors their utility.<sup id="fnref:1:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>

<p> The second major principle of semiconductors is doping. Doping is the act of adding tiny amounts of impurities to the material in order to improve its quality. A “perfect” semiconductor is not as efficient or useful as an impure one as the distance between the valence band and the conduction band may still require too much energy to conduct electricity easily. The impurities are incorporated into the crystalline structure of the material, and with it, bring more electrons. These electrons fill the valence bands, forcing the “extra” electrons into a donor band, which is much closer to the conduction band, requiring less energy for electrons to move to the conduction band. <sup id="fnref:2:1"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup> <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> Impurities can also arrive unintentionally either as an intrinsic trait of the material or through manufacturing.. Being able to control which impurities are added is key to producing effective and lasting semiconductors. <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup></p>

<p> Semiconductor materials have seen an increased usage since their inception and have proven to have practical applications. The ability to finely control the material’s conductivity has seen use in many of the devices that are used nowadays, such as transistors and integrated circuits.2 Efforts in semiconductor research are currently studying the effects of different doping compounds as well as more efficient means of production.<sup id="fnref:3:1"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote" rel="footnote" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup></p>

<hr />

<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Xiao, H. <em>Introduction to semiconductor technology, 2nd Ed.</em>; SPIE; Bellingham, Washington, 2012; 2-60. <a href="#fnref:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref:1:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;<sup>2</sup></a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Tro, N. J.; Fridgen, T. D.; Shaw, L. E. <em>Chemistry: A Molecular Approach, Third Edition.</em>; Pearson: Boston, 2014; 421-422. <a href="#fnref:2" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref:2:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;<sup>2</sup></a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>Haller, E.E &amp; Queisser, H.J. Defects in semiconductors: some fatal, some vital. <em>Science,</em> <strong>1948</strong>, <em>281</em>, 946-950, <a href="#fnref:3" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a> <a href="#fnref:3:1" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;<sup>2</sup></a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>Londos, C.A.; Sgourou, E.N.; Hall, D.; &amp; Chroneos, A. Vacancy-oxygen defects in silicon: the impact of isovalent doping, <em>J. Mater. Sci: Mater. Electron</em> <strong>2014</strong>, 25, 2395-2410. <a href="#fnref:4" class="reversefootnote" role="doc-backlink">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="chemistry" /><category term="circuits" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[an essay I wrote for chemistry. it covers the topics of semiconductor properties and uses.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I am the Universe, and the Universe is Me</title><link href="/2019/09/02/I-am-the-universe.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I am the Universe, and the Universe is Me" /><published>2019-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-02T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/2019/09/02/I-am-the-universe</id><content type="html" xml:base="/2019/09/02/I-am-the-universe.html"><![CDATA[<p>(2022-04-16) hi everyone. this is a little “manifesto” I wrote back in 2019 when I had a sudden epiphany about the world around me. it might be somewhat outdated, so this will likely end up being re-written at another time. however, I enjoyed writing this and would like to share it with everyone.
<br /><br /></p>
<hr />

<p><br /><br /></p>
<h3 id="i-am-the-universe-and-the-universe-is-me">I am the Universe, and the Universe is Me</h3>
<h4 id="a-manifesto-but-mostly-a-collection-of-thoughts">A Manifesto, but Mostly a Collection of Thoughts</h4>

<p> I have been born and have died countless times, and I will continue to do so for all eternity, or at least until the universe ceases to exist. I am unsure of when the latter will or would happen, though that is a debate for another time. Now, I do not mean that I have been reincarnated in the religious sense, such as that seen in Hinduism. I mean something much different. To convey such thoughts, explaining would have to be done beforehand in order for a sufficient context to be given.</p>

<p> I am the universe. I do not mean this in an egotistical way, however. I am not trying to say that I am god. Well, I am. And you, the reader are, too. So are the bacteria on your face, and the animals outside. And so are the viruses and the stars. We are all part of the universe, acting as one conscious unit. Everything that is happening, has happened, or will happen, is because of a series of events that had happened before, affecting everything related, all according to the laws of nature. Everything that exists, including you and I, are expressions of nature, and by extension, the universe. As such, under the right philosphical light, the universe would seem to have some form of intention. And in a sense, that would be correct, since as mentioned before, everything that happens is acting all according the the laws of nature. From cosmic events such as the big bang, to the seemingly insignificant such as what you had eaten for breakfeast, are all affected by such laws. And as such, will also affect future events in a similar manner.</p>

<p> I am not claiming to completely understand the human psyche or even all the laws the cosmos. I am, however, claiming to understand that the universe has fundamental rules that are set in place which everything obeys. Considering that we, and everything else, are in the universe, we are also set to obey these rules. However, it would be innaproptiate to say that we are “in” the universe, strictly speaking. I feel that it would be better fitting to describe us as part of the universe. After all, what is to separate you from a chair, or the sun, or the countless nebulae? The answer at first may seem obvious. “I am made of flesh, bones, and blood, that chair is made of wood, the sun is made of plasma, and the nebulae are made of cosmic dust.” This idea, I feel, would be giving the universe a disservice. Think about the question again, but think of such things at a fundamental level. Yes, you are made of flesh. And the chair is made of wood. But what is your flesh made of? What is that of the wood? Flesh is made of elements, atoms. Such elements are also seen in wood, plasma, and cosmic dust. “But I have a brain, a consciousness,” you might think. I am not here to debate that, for that is true. You are thinking, so you must have a consciousness. However, your brain, or the peripheral for your consciousness for that matter, is made of the same materials as everything else. It just so happens to be arranged in a matter that allows for your stream of conscious thought to be manifested through action. Does this mean that everything else has the potential for conscious thought? Yes, if it were to be arranged in such a way. Our brains are simply machines created by the universe, obeying the laws of nature in the same exact way everything else does. The copper in a computer has the potential of being copper that is used as a roof, but because of its current circumstance is used being used a certain way.</p>

<p> What I was trying to convey with the previous paragraph is that you and I are the same. That I am the same as that chair, or the sun, or the nebulae. Everything, at the end of the day, is made of the same fundamental parts, just being utilized differently. However, the parts that make up “you” are not going to permanently stay that way. We are constantly changing and shifting, including the universe. The parts that make up “you” have been in countless other arrangments before. And the cycle will repeat. They will be used in countless arrangements after. But at the same time, they are still you. But what separates you from everything else? After all, we just established that everything is one and the same. The answer is nothing, really. Nothing really separates you from a chair, the sun, or the nebulae. But because of that, you  <strong><em>are</em></strong> the chair. You are the sun, and you are the nebulae. You are the universe. You were created as a manifestation of it, and so is everything else. You are the universe, and the universe is you. Though our bodies and minds may die and rot, we will continue to exist in this cosmic dance until the end of time.</p>

<p> As mentioned before, the universe would seem to have intention based on the way it acts (as it follows the laws of nature and we are expressions of such laws). However, it is also possible to view the universe as without intention. Just like our brains, the universe is simply following a predetermined set of rules. It did not nessesarily mean to create us, the stars, or Earth. It simply did so as a side effect of abiding to the laws of nature. So with that said, it would seem that we were created as expressions of nature, unintentionally. However, the laws of nature could be interpreted as intention, so in a sense, the universe is with and without intention. It does things according to its laws.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="philosophy" /><category term="pantheism" /><category term="personal" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A Manifesto, but Mostly a Collection of Thoughts]]></summary></entry></feed>