<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-04-14T21:15:54-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">gerard’s site</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">An Analysis of the Brain-in-a-Vat Argument</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/17/biv-analysis.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Analysis of the Brain-in-a-Vat Argument" /><published>2021-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/12/17/biv-analysis</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/12/17/biv-analysis.html">&lt;p&gt; Suppose that a character, Bivvie, is a brain in a vat (BIV) – Bivvie’s reality is “false” as it is constructed by some external actor by feeding Bivvie’s brain different signals that are used to construct their reality. Despite actually being a BIV, Putnam argues that Bivvie is completely unable to actually say that they are a BIV. This conclusion draws from two key ideas: resemblance and intention/depiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; To explain both of these ideas, we will use one of Putnam’s examples: suppose that an ant is walking along the ground, unknowingly leaving a line behind in the dirt. Miracuously, the image that the ant has left behind bears a striking resemblance to the former Prime Minster of the UK, Winston Churchill. If one were then asked, did the ant depict Winston Churchil? Intuitively, most people would say no. This is due to the simple fact that despite the ant’s “drawing” resembling Churchill, it did not intend to draw Churchill. Churchill is far beyond the ant’s limited knowledge – the ant is unaware of who Churchill is, or even the fact that it was “drawing” anything to begin with. This examples serves to illustrate how resemblance is not a sufficient condition for depiction. The ant’s drawing resembles that of a person, but that does not imply that it is a depiction of a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; We can further build apon this logic using a more abstract conjecture. Suppose that you are having a conversation with an atrificial intelligence, programmed to perfectly replicate human discourse. If one were to ask it, “How is the weather today?” it may reply, “It is very windy today.” If we are to strip away the AI’s interface what would be left is a program – an algorithm designed to react in a specific way given a certain stimulus. The fact that the AI spoke about the weather like a human does not mean that it “knows” about the weather. Simply put, the AI has no idea of what weather is. The AI has never experienced the weather as we have – it is simply reading data. To further exemplify this, if I were to ask the AI, “Do you like the weather today?” and it were to respond, “Yes, I like how windy it is today,” the AI does not “like” the “weather”. To the AI, what it interprets as the “weather” is far removed from our experience of the weather. Similar to the situation with the ant, the AI’s words bear resemblance to an understanding of the weather, but they do not actually depict a person who has experienced the weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; With this context in mind, it is now possible give a proper analysis of the BIV situation. If Bivvie were to say, “I am a brain in a vat,” the statement is inherently false. This again draws from the key ideas of resemblance and depiction. Suppose that Bivvie’s reality is controlled by a mad scientist who is feeding signals to Bivvie’s brain, and that this mad scientist exists in a world similar to ours, with the certainty that he is not a BIV. If Bivvie (in their falsified reality) points at a tree, what are they truly saying? The tree that they are pointing at is a simulated tree (sTree). They are unable to point at it and say that it is a real tree (rTree) without the statement being false. So the statement “That is a tree,” implicitly turns into “That is an sTree.” This logic extends to when Bivvie questions the nature of their reality as well. If Bivvie says that “I am a BIV,” their statement refers to a simulated BIV-scenario (sBIV) and not a “real” BIV-scenario (rBIV). Similar to the tree, the statement “I am a BIV” implicitly turns into “I am an sBIV,” which is inherently false. Even if Bivvie were to say, “I am an rBIV, ” it would then be the same as saying, “I am in srBIV,” as Bivvie has only ever experienced what it is like in their falsified reality. As such, Bivvie has as no concept of what an “rBIV” would be. They can imagine the concept of one, the limited scope of their knowledge means that anything they can conceptualize will implicitly be a “simulated” version. Bivvie’s statement merely resembles that of a “real” “I am a BIV” statement, and does not actually depict one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Putnam, Hilary (1999). Brains in a Vat. In Sven Bernecker &amp;amp; Fred I. Dretske (eds.), &lt;em&gt;Knowledge: Readings in Contemporary Epistemology.&lt;/em&gt; Oxford University Press. pp. 1-21.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="philosophy" /><category term="simulation-theory" /><summary type="html">an essay detailing my thoughts on simulation theory and the BIV argument.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">On the Function and Mechanisms of Semiconductor Materials</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On the Function and Mechanisms of Semiconductor Materials" /><published>2021-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2021-11-05T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2021/11/05/semiconductor-materials.html">&lt;p&gt; Society is filled to the brim with a plethora of electrical devices, such as computers, phones, and even simple calculators. Such technology is made possible through the application of semiconductor materials. A semiconductor is a material that has an electrical conductivity that lies between that of an electrical conductor (mainly metals, such as copper and aluminum) and an electrical insulator (such as rubber or wood), with the most common semiconductor materials being silicon and germanium. Semiconductor materials operate on two main principles: bandgap and doping. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Everything in the universe is composed of atoms. Atoms have electron orbitals, also known as shells which can be thought of as the “path” that an electron takes when orbiting around the atoms’ nucleus. When atoms combine on the macroscopic level, the shells combine together to form bands. The filled, lower energy orbitals are known as the valence band. Electrons in the valence band are still bound too strongly to their atoms’ nucleus, and can not conduct an electric current. The empty, higher energy orbitals are known as the conduction bands. The electrons, when in the conduction bands, require little energy to move freely and can conduct an electric current. The distance between the valence band and the conduction band is known as the material’s bandgap, and is responsible for a material’s conductivity. Electrically resistant materials have a very high bandgap, while electrically conductive materials have a very low bandgap. Semiconductive materials have a bandgap that lies between that of a resistor and a conductor, so adding energy to the system (e.g. heating) allows the electrons to more easily move to the conduction band. It is the ability to control the material’s conductivity that gives semiconductors their utility.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The second major principle of semiconductors is doping. Doping is the act of adding tiny amounts of impurities to the material in order to improve its quality. A “perfect” semiconductor is not as efficient or useful as an impure one as the distance between the valence band and the conduction band may still require too much energy to conduct electricity easily. The impurities are incorporated into the crystalline structure of the material, and with it, bring more electrons. These electrons fill the valence bands, forcing the “extra” electrons into a donor band, which is much closer to the conduction band, requiring less energy for electrons to move to the conduction band. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Impurities can also arrive unintentionally either as an intrinsic trait of the material or through manufacturing.. Being able to control which impurities are added is key to producing effective and lasting semiconductors. &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Semiconductor materials have seen an increased usage since their inception and have proven to have practical applications. The ability to finely control the material’s conductivity has seen use in many of the devices that are used nowadays, such as transistors and integrated circuits.2 Efforts in semiconductor research are currently studying the effects of different doping compounds as well as more efficient means of production.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Xiao, H. &lt;em&gt;Introduction to semiconductor technology, 2nd Ed.&lt;/em&gt;; SPIE; Bellingham, Washington, 2012; 2-60. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Tro, N. J.; Fridgen, T. D.; Shaw, L. E. &lt;em&gt;Chemistry: A Molecular Approach, Third Edition.&lt;/em&gt;; Pearson: Boston, 2014; 421-422. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Haller, E.E &amp;amp; Queisser, H.J. Defects in semiconductors: some fatal, some vital. &lt;em&gt;Science,&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;1948&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;281&lt;/em&gt;, 946-950, &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Londos, C.A.; Sgourou, E.N.; Hall, D.; &amp;amp; Chroneos, A. Vacancy-oxygen defects in silicon: the impact of isovalent doping, &lt;em&gt;J. Mater. Sci: Mater. Electron&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;2014&lt;/strong&gt;, 25, 2395-2410. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="essay" /><category term="chemistry" /><category term="circuits" /><summary type="html">an essay I wrote for chemistry. it covers the topics of semiconductor properties and uses.</summary></entry></feed>